Guide to the C. Harrison Mann, Jr. papers, 1950-1977
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
C. Harrison Mann, Jr. papers
1950-1977
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Charles Harrison Mann, Jr., 1908-1977
C0094
85.5 linear feet (65 boxes)
Comprises C. Harrison Mann, Jr.'s personal papers and handwritten draft of his history of George Mason University. Papers pertain to his political career and include subject files, memoranda, campaign materials, speeches, newsclippings and other related materials.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by Betty Hart Mann in 1979.
Biographical Information
Charles Harrison Mann, Jr. was born in Alabama in 1908 and received his law degree from the University of Virginia in 1931. He subsequently became an attorney both in Washington, D.C. and in Arlington, Virginia where he and his wife Betty Hart Mann, maintained their home. In 1949, while serving as President of the Northern Virginia Chapter of the University of Virginia Alumni Association, Mann organized an exploratory committee of local citizens to develop support for higher education in Northern Virginia. Through these efforts, the Northern Virginia Center of the University opened in October 1, 1949.
In 1953 Mann organized the Advisory Council to the Northern Virginia Center, which agreed that a two-year branch college should be established. Elected as a Democrat to the Virginia House of Delegates from 1954-1970, Mann sponsored a resolution calling for a study of educational needs for Virginia, and was instrumental in recommending the development of a college system in Virginia, particularly the establishment of a branch in Northern Virginia.
Mann was responsible for creating an educational financial assistance program for Virginia college students, and was instrumental in sponsoring legislation allowing local governments to form regional boards to acquire and transfer land and buildings for educational use.
He also served as the Chairman of George Mason College's first Board of Control. He sponsored bills constituting George Mason College as a branch of the University of Virginia and later elevating it to a four year division of the University with the right to grant degrees and offer graduate program. He served on the GMU Board of Visitors from 1975 to 1977. He died in 1977.
Scope and Content
Comprises C. Harrison Mann, Jr.'s personal papers and handwritten draft of his history of George Mason University. Papers pertain to his political career and include subject files, memoranda, campaign materials, speeches, newsclippings and other related materials.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically according to subject.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds other personal papers and orgnizational records on the politics of Northern Virginia as well as the George Mason University archives. In addition, there is the C. Harrison Mann, Jr. collection of rare books and atlases that can be found searching the GMU Libraries catalog as well as the C. Harrison Mann, Jr. Digitized Map Collection.
Alternative Form Available
Selections from the C. Harrison Mann papers are also available in the C. Harrison Mann, Jr. Digital Collection.
Index Terms
Persons:
Mann, Charles Harrison, Jr., 1908-1977.
Corporate Names:
George Mason University.
Geographical Names:
Virginia--Politics and government--20th century.
Subjects:
Education--Political aspects--Virginia.
Contents List
- C. Harrison Mann, Jr. Collection
  - Almond J. Lindsay 1956 - 69. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Attorney General Opinions 1935 - 67. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Byrd, Sen. Harry F. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence General Assembly 1954 - 55. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence 1954 - 55 General Assembly. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence 1954 - 55 General Assembly. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence 1954 - 55 General Assembly. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence 1954 - 55 General Assembly. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence 1956. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence 1956. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence 1956. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence 1961. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence 1961. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence 1962. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence 1962. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence 1965 General Assembly. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence 1965 General Assembly. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence 1966 General Assembly. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence 1966 General Assembly. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence 1966 General Assembly. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence 1966. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence 1966. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence 1966. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence 1966. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence 1966. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence 1967. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence 1967. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence 1967. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence 1967. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence 1967. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence 1967. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence 1967. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence 1967. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence 1967. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence 1967. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence 1967. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence 1967. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence 1967. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Misc. 1940's Correspondence. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - General Assembly 1960 Correspondence. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - General Assembly 1960 Correspondence. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - General Assembly 1960 Correspondence. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence 1963. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence 1963. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence 1963. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence 1963. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence 1964. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence 1964. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence 1964. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence 1964. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence 1964. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence 1964. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence 1964. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence 1964. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence 1965. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence 1965. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence 1965. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence 1965. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence 1965. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence 1968 General Assembly. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence 1968 General Assembly. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence 1968 General Assembly. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence 1968 General Assembly. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence 1968 General Assembly. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - General Correspondence. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Complimentary Lectures. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Moncure Bill (Personal). (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Moncure Bill (Personal). (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Misc. 1950's Correspondence. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Misc. 1950's Correspondence. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Personal Campaign Correspondence - 1953. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Lectures. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence 1957. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence 1957. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence 1958 General. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence 1958 General. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence 1959. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence 1961. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence 1961. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 1962 Correspondence. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - General Assembly 1963 Correspondence. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - General Assembly 1963 Correspondence. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence 1968. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence 1968. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence 1969. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence 1969. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence 1969. (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence 1970. (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Life May 1950. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Holiday May 1950. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Press Releases - Personal -1953. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, General, Prior to 1956. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1958 Richmond - Times Dispatch. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - The Virginian. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Harrison - Albertis S. 1961. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings - 1962 General Assembly. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Press Releases - 1963. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1964. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1964 - 65. (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - General Assembly 1966 Clippings. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - General Assembly 1966 Clippings. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1967. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1967. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1967. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Goha Warren Cooke. (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Howell - Henry E. Jr. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Moore, E. Blackburn. (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Willy - Sen, E. E. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Invitations - Prior to Current Year. (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Invitation: Current Year. (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Invitations Misc. (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Invitation Misc. (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Press Releases Council and Democratic Exec. Comm. (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Press Releases Council and Democratic Exec. Comm. (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Press Releases. (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Press Releases. (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1950's. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1950's. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1958 Press Clippings. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 1958 Press Clippings. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 1963 Speaking Engagement. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 1963 Speech Material. (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Speeches - 1965 Campaign. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1968. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1968. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1968. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1968. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1968. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Clippings 1969. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper Clippings. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Personal News clippings (1 Small One). (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Headlines - Mann's Donation of Atlases to GMU. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - General Reports (Misc. Topics). (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Counties. (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Mary Marshall (Delegate, her Newsletter, Printed material). (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Echols - Sen. M. Patton. (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Organizations - Lists. (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Lists. (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Lists. (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - League of Women Voters - Arlington. (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Speeches. (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Speeches. (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Speeches. (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Jefferson Day Banquet 1957. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Jefferson Day Banquet 1958. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Jefferson Day Banquet 1959 - 60. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Jefferson Jackson Celebration 1961. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Jefferson Jackson Day Dinner 1962 - 64. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - 10th District Committee. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Master Address List. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Master Address List. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Master Address List. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Misc. Address List. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Master Address List. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Master Address List. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Names, Addresses. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Names, Addresses. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Precinct List. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Precinct List. (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Women Club. (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Democratic Coalition. (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Platform Promises 1963. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Previous Campaigns 1963. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Republican Record 1963. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Democratic Records. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Republican Statements. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Campaign 1963. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Campaign Misc. 1963. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Campaign Misc. 1963. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - 1963 Campaign. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - 1963 Campaign. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - 1964 Campaign. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - 1964 Campaign. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Factual Information. (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Clips, Facts - Campaign 1965. (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Clips, Facts - Campaign 1965. (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - 1965 Campaign - Exec. Committee. (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - 1965 Committee Candidate. (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - 1965 Campaign. (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - 1965 Campaign. (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - 1965 Campaign. (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Facts. (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Misc. Issues 1964. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 1965 Campaign. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1965 Campaign. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - 1965 Campaign. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - 1965 Campaign. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - 1965 Campaign. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Campaign Material Armistead Boothe. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Boothe, Armistead - Campaign Material. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Campaign Material. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Campaign 1966. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Campaign 1966. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Campaign 1966. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Campaign 1966. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Campaign 1966. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Campaign 1966. (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Campaigns 1955 - 58. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Campaigns 1955 - 58. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Campaigns 1955 - 58. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Campaigns 1955 - 58. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Campaigns 1955 - 58. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Campaigns 1955 - 58. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Campaigns 1958. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Campaigns 1958. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Campaigns 1959 - 60. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Campaigns 1959 - 60. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Campaigns 1959 - 60. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Campaigns 1959 - 60. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Campaigns 1960. (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Endorsements Elections. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Campaign 1955 Elections #3. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Campaign 1955 Elections #2. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Campaign 1955 Elections #1. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Campaign 1956. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Campaign 1956. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Campaign 1956. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Campaign 1960. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Campaign 1960. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Campaign 1960. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Campaign 1960. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Campaign 1961. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Campaign 1961. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Campaign 1961. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Campaign 1961. (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Campaign 1961. (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Campaign 1950 Elections. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Campaign 1951 Elections. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Campaign 1952 Elections Folder #1. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Campaign 1952 Elections Folder #2. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Campaign 1953 Elections. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Campaign Costs - 1953. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Campaign 1961. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Campaign 1962. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Campaign 1968. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Campaign 1968. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Campaign for State Senate March 11, 1969. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Campaign for State Senate March 11, 1969. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Campaign 1969. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Campaign 1969. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Candidates. (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Campaign II. (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Campaign Material. (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Schedule. (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Convention, City and State 1952. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Conventions 1953 - 54. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Conventions 1956. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Conventions 1959 (June 23). (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Convention May 2, 1960. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - General 1963. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Publicity GOP 1963. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Convention May 28, 1964. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - County Convention 1964. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Demo. Convention 1964. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Campaign 1967. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Campaign 1967. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Campaign 1967. (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Campaign 1967. (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Campaign 1967. (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Campaign 1967. (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Resolutions ( Demo, Exec. Comm.). (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - D.E.C: 1947. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - D.E.C: 1948 Demo Council and Exec. Comm. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - D.E.C: 1949 Demo Council and Exec. Comm. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Filings D.E.C: 1949 Elections. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - D.E.C: 1950 Demo Council and Exec. Comm. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Filings, D.E.C: 1951 Elections. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Minutes: 1951 - 48 D.E.C: 1949 Demo Council and Exec. Comm. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Democratic Exec. Committee. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Republican Propaganda Elections. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Republican Propaganda Elections - File 2. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Democratic Committee. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Democratic Committee Arlington 1964. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - County Board Elections. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Oath Forms - Democratic Committee 1965 - 1966. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Democratic Executive Comm. 1965, 1967. (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Democratic Executive Comm. 1965, 1967. (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Democratic Executive Comm. 1967 - 1968. (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Arlington Co.Democratic Committee " Lynching - 1968". (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Congressional Campaign - Elections 1954. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Election Laws - VA. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Party Plans - Elections. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Democratic Party Plans. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Election Expenses. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Battle For Governor 1969. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Battle For Governor 1969. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Inauguration - 1954 and 1958. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - 1962 Inauguration 1966. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Primary Elections 1953. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Primary Elections 1955. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Primary 1957. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Primary 1959. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Primary 1959. (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Primary 1961 - Democratic Exec. Committee. (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Primary 1961 - Democratic Exec. Committee. (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Primary 1961 - Democratic Exec. Committee. (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Primary 1961 - Democratic Exec. Committee. (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Primary Forms (Declaration of Candidacy - Committee and State offices). (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Primary Elections 1945. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Primary Elections 1947. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Primary Elections 1949. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Primary Elections 1950. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Primary Elections 1951. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Primary Elections 1952. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Primary Elections 1953 (Fenwick Incl). (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Primary Elections 1954. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Primary 1955 II, Elections, "Law of Descents". (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Primary (Gilner) 1957. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Primary (Gilner) 1957. (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Petitions - Forms. (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Agitators 1965 - Clippings. (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Misc. Letters and Reports. (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - VEPCO 1965. (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - State Police. (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Teaching Scholarships. (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Civil Rights. (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Civil Rights. (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Civil Rights. (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - VA. Commission on Constitutional Govt. (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Welfare. (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Civil War (Ga). (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Sex Education. (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Scholarships. (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Republicans. (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Republicans. (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Republicans. (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Retarded Children. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - 1963 - Biographical. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Questionnaires 1963. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Birch. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Voting Rights. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Godwin, Mills E. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Abused Children. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Nazi Charter. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Conflict of Interest 1964. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Nazi Party. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Pesticides 1964. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Liquor. (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Screeners - 1962. (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - VA. Protective Force. (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - VA. Protective Force. (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - W.W.II. (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - ABC 1965. (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Metropolitan. (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Civilian Defense. (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Civilian Defense. (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Civil Defense. (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Civil Defense. (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Civil Defense. (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - NAACP. (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - NAACP. (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - NAACP. (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - NAACP Jacket #2. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Potomac River. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Potomac River. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Potomac River. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Poll - Public School Integration. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Fairfax Hospital. (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Harrison v. Day (Court Case). (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Harrison v. Day (Court Case). (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - History. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Housing. (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Institutions, Colleges, Hospitals. (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Institutions - Panel, Rehabilitative (Hospitals, Colleges). (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Investigations. (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Labor. (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Joshen Pass. (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Guns. (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Hahn Commissions. (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Health - Medical Care. (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Liquor 1968. (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Open Housing. (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Open Housing. (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Plastic Bags 1968. (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Rules. (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Pornography. (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Riots 1968. (Box 18, Folder 1A)
  - Riots 1968. (Box 18, Folder 1B)
  - Communist Organizations. (Box 18, Folder 2A)
  - Communist Organizations. (Box 18, Folder 2B)
  - Communist Organizations. (Box 18, Folder 3A)
  - Communist Organizations. (Box 18, Folder 3B)
  - Communism Periodicals. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Communism Racial Integration. (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Communism Racial Integration. (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Al Crowe 1959 - County Board. (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Virginia Info. (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Info. (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Info. (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Arlington Democratic Forum. (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Congratulations. (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - C0-Ops. (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Defenders. (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Awards. (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Liquor By The Drink 1966. (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Questionnaires. (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Committee of 100. (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Children's Home Society of VA. (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Antiques. (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Women (misc). (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Map - Arlington Directory - State Officials Letter - "Know your Senator". (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Members AELE. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Directors - Advisory Committee - AELE. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Names - AELE. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - AELE Advisory Committee - Prospects. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Mass Evacuation Plans. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Mass Evacuation Data - Published. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Mass Evacuation Data - Published. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Evacuation Memoranda. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Evacuation Committee. (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Evacuation Press Released. (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Missing. (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Evacuation Minutes, D. C. and No. VA. (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - George Mason 1965 - 71 Clippings. (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - G.M.U 1964 - 71 (misc). (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - G.M.U 1964 - 71 (misc). (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - G.M.U Correspondence 1964 - 71. (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - G.M.U Correspondence 1964 - 71. (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - G.M.U Correspondence. (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - G.M.U Dedication 1964. (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - G.M.U advisory Board. (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - G.M.U advisory Board. (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - G.M.U budget 1965 - 72. (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - G.M.U Info. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - G.M.U Info. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - G.M.U Info. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - G.M.U Info. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlets on Universities and Colleges, G.M.U handbook. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - G.M.U Newspapers May 1969 - May 1971. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - G.M.U Newspapers May 1969 - May 1971. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - G.M.U Advisory Board. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - G.M.U Board of Visitors. (Box 20, Folder 9)